--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
字幕翻译：CMCT字幕组 后期处理：不死别姬
卡 洛 克 影 业
马 里 奥 · 凯 萨
出 品
西 太 平 洋
制 片
亮 光 风 暴 娱 乐
联 合 制 片
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
电 影 作 品
洛杉矶  西元2029年
30亿人死于1997年8月29日
Three billion human lives ended on August 29, 1997.
这场核战的幸存者
The survivors of the nuclear fire...
称这天为"审判日"
called the war "Judgment Day."
他们虽然活着  却得面对新恶梦
They lived only to face a new nightmare...
打一场跟机器人的战争
the war against the machines.
电脑机器人的主宰者  天网
The computer which controlled the machines, Skynet...
派了两名终结者回到过去
sent two Terminators back through time.
它们的任务是消灭反抗军的领袖
Their mission: to destroy the leader of the human resistance.
约翰·康纳  我的儿子
John Connor, my son.
1984年  第一个终结者想杀死我
The first Terminator was programmed to strike at me in the year 1984...
那是在约翰出生之前
before John was born.
但它失败了
It failed.
第二个则是试图
The second was set to strike at John himself...
杀害童年的约翰
when he was still a child.
同上次一样  反抗军也派了一位勇士
As before, the resistance was able to send a lone warrior...
来保卫约翰
a protector for John.
问题是谁能先找到约翰
It was just a question of which one of them would reach him first.
阿 诺 · 施 瓦 辛 格
终 结 者 2
审 判 日
琳 达 · 汉 密 尔 顿
罗 伯 特 · 帕 特 里 克
乔 · 莫 顿
阿 尔 · 伯 恩
埃 帕 莎 · 默 克 森
丹 尼 · 库 克 塞
卡 斯 图 罗 · 格 雷 拉
特 别 介 绍
爱 德 华 · 福 隆
选 角
玛 利 · 费 恩
服 装 设 计
玛 莉 妮 · 斯 图 尔 特
配 乐
布 拉 德 · 费 德 尔
工 业 光 魔
视 觉 特 效 总 监
丹 尼 斯 · 穆 伦
特 效 化 妆 及 终 结 者 视 效
制 作 总 监
斯 坦 · 温 斯 顿
剪 辑
康 拉 德 · 巴 夫
马 克 · 高 德 布 拉 特
理 查 德 · A · 哈 里 斯
艺 术 指 导
约 瑟 夫 · 奈 米 克 三 世
摄 影 指 导
亚 当 · 格 林 伯 格
联 合 制 片
B · J · 若克
丝 黛 芬 妮 · 奥 斯 汀
执 行 制 片
盖 尔 · 安 妮 · 赫 德
以 及
马 里 奥 · 凯 萨
编 剧
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
威 廉 · 威 舍 尔
制 片 及 导 演
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
"体格符合"
我需要你的衣服  靴子  机车
I need your clothes, your boots and your motorcycle.
你忘记说"请"字了
You forgot to say please.
救我呀
Get him off me!
把刀子拔出来
Pull it out!
快拔出来
拿去
Take it.
你不能这样一走了之
Can't let you take the man's wheels, son.
把机车留下  不然要你好看
Now, get off before I put you down.
这才像话  混蛋
That's it, goddamn it.
六号报告
R-31 David, Sherman Code 6...
六街桥与圣塔菲之间有电流干扰
at the Sixth Street Bridge and Santa Fe on electrical disturbance.
10-4  R-31  D
Ten-four, R-31 David.
"查询: 约翰·康纳"
"白种男性  10岁"
"前科: 非法入侵  偷窃"
"母亲: 莎拉康纳  父亲: 不详"
"法定监护人: 柏陶德夫妇"
约翰  快进去把你的房间弄干净
John, get in there and clean up that pigsty of yours.
她真是惹人烦  不是吗?
Your foster parents are kind of dicks, huh?
我真受够了那可恶的小鬼
I swear, I have had it with that goddamn kid.
- 他甚至不肯回我的话  - 你挡住电视了
- He won't even answer me anymore. - Honey, move.
你得帮我管教他
Would you get off your butt and help me?
- 陶德  - 什么事?
- Todd! - What?
他有一个月没整理房间了
He hasn't cleaned that room of his in a month.
原来是急事  我这就去说说他吧
Oh, it's an emergency. Hang on. I'll get right on it.
- 走吧  - 约翰
- Come on. - John.
进去  照你妈的话做
Get your ass inside. Do what your mother tells you.
她不是我妈  陶德
She's not my mother, Todd.
"州立精神病院"
下一位病人非常有趣
This next patient is interesting.
我观察这病例数年了
I've been following the case for years.
女性  29岁
A 29-year-old female...
诊断结果是精神不正常
diagnosed as acute schizo-affective disorder.
她有一般的症状: 沮丧  焦虑  暴力倾向
The usual indicators: depression, anxiety, violent acting out...
迫害妄想症
delusions of persecution.
但她的心态却非常独特
The delusional architecture is fairly unique.
她相信一种叫终结者的机器
She believes that a machine called the Terminator...
这玩意儿的外形和人类相同
which looks human, of course,
它是乘时光倒流机回来杀她的
was sent back through time to kill her.
蛮有独创性的
That's original.
她孩子的父亲也是乘倒流机
And also that the father of her child...
回到今日来保卫她的一位战士
was a soldier sent back to protect her.
他也是从未来回来的
He was from the future too.
我没记错的话  是2029年
The year 2029, if I remember correctly.
我们到了
And here we are.
早安  莎拉
Morning, Sarah.
早安  索大夫
Good morning, Dr. Silberman.
你的膝盖还好吗?
How's the knee?
很好  莎拉
Fine, Sarah.
数周前她夺走我的笔
She stabbed me in the kneecap...
攻击了我的膝盖骨
with my pen a few weeks ago.
她曾多次意图脱逃
Repeated escape attempts.
咱们继续参观
Let's move on, shall we?
我不喜欢病人把房间搞乱
I don't like to see the patients disrupting their rooms like this.
要确定她有服用镇定剂
See she takes her Thorazine.
没问题  索大夫  我会搞定她的
Sure, Dr. Silberman. I'll take care of it.
吃药的时间到了
It's time to take your meds, Connor.
拿走
You take it.
吃了药病会好
Now you know you gotta be good.
下午你还要复查
You're up for review this afternoon.
我不想吃
I'm not taking it, Dougie.
- 更不想有什么麻烦  - 不会有麻烦的
- I don't want any trouble. - Ain't no trouble.
电击她
Zap her.
快点吃  宝贝
Last call, sugar.
睡个好觉
Sweet dreams.
你是约翰·康纳的法定监护人?
Are you the legal guardian of John Connor?
是的  警员  他又惹祸了?
That's right, Officer. What's he done now?
我可以和他谈谈吗?
Could I speak with him, please?
他若在家  当然可以
You could if he were here.
但今早他骑车出去了
He took off on his bike this morning.
不知跑哪儿去了
He could be anywhere.
你有约翰的照片吗?
Do you have a photograph of John?
有  等一下
Yeah. Hold on.
能告诉我这是怎么回事吗?
Gonna tell me what this is about?
我只想问他一些问题
I just need to ask him a few questions.
他长得真俊俏
He's a good-looking boy.
我留着照片你不介意吧?
Do you mind if I keep this picture?
不  当然不会
No, go on.
今早也有个人来找他
There was a guy here this morning looking for him too.
对  骑机车的大个子
Yeah, a big guy on a bike.
他跟这件事有关吗?
Has that got something to do with this?
没有
No.
不用管他
I wouldn't worry about him.
多谢你们的合作
Thanks for your cooperation.
请插入金融卡
Please insert your stolen card now.
密码是
PIN number.
快点  搞太久了
Hurry up. This is taking too long.
加油
Go, baby.
好
All right.
- 密码  9003  - 你这是跟谁学的?
- PIN number 9003. - Where'd you learn this stuff from?
我妈  我亲生母亲
From my mom. My real mom, I mean.
提三百元
Withdraw 300 bucks.
来吧  宝贝
Come on, baby. Come on!
- 好  - 成功了
- Yes! - Hey, it worked.
好  赚到了  走
All right. Easy money. Come on!
轻而易举
Yes! Piece of cake.
- 她就是你妈?  - 是的
- Is that her? - Yes.
她似乎很酷嘛
She's pretty cool, huh?
不  她是个神精病
No, she's a complete psycho.
所以才被人关在精神病院
That's why she's at Pescadero. It's a mental institute.
她企图炸毁一间电脑工厂
She tried to blow up a computer factory,
结果遭击伤被捕
but got shot and arrested.
真糟
No shit.
她是彻底的失败者
She's a total loser.
走  咱们去花点钱
Come on. Let's go spend some money.
莎拉
Sarah.
莎拉  醒醒
Sarah, wake up.
凯尔
Kyle.
你不是死了吗?
You're dead.
我们的孩子呢?
Where's our son, Sarah?
被他们带走了
They took him away from me.
- 他处在危险之中  - 我知道
- He's the target now. - I know.
他孤立无援  你要去保护他
He's all alone. You have to protect him.
我知道
I know.
你教我怎么办
You tell me how I'm supposed to do that.
他对我没有信心
He doesn't even believe me anymore.
- 我已经失去他了  - 你有能力
- I've lost him. - You're strong, Sarah.
比你认为的更有力量
Stronger than you ever thought you could be.
起来抗争  战士
On your feet, soldier!
我爱你  莎拉  永远爱你
I love you, Sarah. I always will.
- 我需要你  - 我永远在你左右
- I need you. - I'll always be with you.
还记得我的话吗?
Remember the message?
一切尚未成为定局
The future is not set.
未来仍可以自己去开创
There is no fate but what we make for ourselves.
别离开我
Stay with me.
留给世界的时间所剩无几
There's not much time left in the world, Sarah.
凯尔  别走
Kyle, don't go!
凯尔
Kyle.
我的眼睛
It's like a giant strobe light...
感到一阵灼热感
burning right through my eyes.
但我似乎仍能看见
Somehow I can still see.
老天
Oh, God.
你们知道我的梦境每晚都一样
We know the dream's the same every night.
- 何必要...  - 请继续
- Why do I have to... - Please continue.
孩子们像纸一样的燃烧
Children look like burnt paper.
一片漆黑
Black.
无人幸免
Not moving.
一切东西都被烧得面目全非
And then the blast wave hits them.
像树叶般四处散落
And they fly apart like leaves.
你的梦把世界末日
Dreams of cataclysm, the end of the world...
描述地很好
are very common.
这不是梦  这场核战是真的
It's not a dream, you moron. It's real.
- 我知道这一切将要发生  - 你的梦很有真实感
- I know the date it happens. - I'm sure it feels real to you.
1997年8月29日那天
On August 29, 1997...
你也会有完全一样的感受
it's gonna feel pretty fuckin' real to you too!
没有擦几万层防晒油的人都会很惨的
Anybody not wearing two-million sunblock is gonna have a real bad day.
- 懂吗?  - 别激动
- Get it? - Stop.
你们无能为力
God, you think you're safe and alive.
你们都会死掉
You're already dead. Everybody!
听好  你们都会死掉
Him. You. You're dead already.
这儿的一切将消失无踪
This whole place, everything you see is gone!
做梦的人是你们  我保证  你们若再不清醒
You're the one living in the dream, 'cause I know it happens!
就"美梦"成真了
It happens!
我现在好多了
I feel much better now.
清醒了
Clearer.
没错  你最近的态度
Yes, your attitude has been...
的确改善不少
much improved lately.
你说我的生活应该有个目标
It's helped me to have a goal...
找件我很希望做的事
something to look forward to.
什么事?
What is that?
你说过
Well, you said...
我的病情若有改善
that if I showed improvement after six months...
你会送我到管理较松的医院
you would transfer me to the minimum security wing...
而且可以让我会客
and I could have visitors.
现在已经过去六个月了
Well, it's been six months and...
我很想见见我儿子
I was looking forward to seeing my son.
我明白了
I see.
咱们再谈谈你提到的终结者机器
Let's go back to what you were saying about those Terminator machines.
你现在认为它们不存在了?
Now you think they don't exist?
它们不存在  我现在知道了
They don't exist. I know that now.
你反覆提及砸烂过一个终结者
But you've told me on many occasions about how you crushed one...
那又怎么解释
in a hydraulic press.
我若做过这事  应该会有证据留下
If I had, there would have been some evidence.
他们应该会在那工厂找到残骸
They would have found something at the factory.
我懂了
I see.
你不认为电脑公司掩饰了一切?
So you don't believe anymore that the company covered it up?
不  它们为何要如此?
No. Why would they?
- 换个位置  - 好
- Let's try a new position right there. - Okay.
所有感应系统运作正常
对  这是新的零件
线路有点故障
戴森先生
Mr. Dyson?
材料小组准备要...
The materials team is running another...
- 戴森先生  - 怎么啦?
- Mr. Dyson. - Yes?
材料小组下午要做实验
The materials team is running another series this afternoon.
你得签字同意
You have to sign for the... it.
- 把"它"拿出来  - 好的  我懂了
- You have to sign it out. - Okay. I'll get it.
戴森先生
Listen, Mr. Dyson,
我知道我刚进公司
I know I haven't been here long,
但你是否可以告诉我...
but I was wondering if you know...
告诉你什么?
Know what?
你知不知道"它"是哪儿来的?
If you know where "it" came from.
我也问过这个问题
I asked them the same question once.
他们的回答是
You know what they told me?
"别问"
Don't ask.
你好  戴森先生
Good morning, Mr. Dyson.
- 还好吗?  - 还好
- How's it going? - Okay.
插入钥匙  左向  三
Insert key. Left on three.
二  一  转
Two, one, turn.
- 你老婆孩子还好吧  - 很好  谢谢
- How are the wife and kids? - Great. Thanks.
好了
Here you go.
你觉得如何  大夫?
So what do you think, Doctor?
我有进步  是吧?
Haven't I shown improvement?
莎拉  问题是
Well, Sarah, here's the problem.
我知道你有多聪明
I know how smart you are.
你是挑我爱听的讲
You're just telling me what I want to hear.
我认为你根本言不由衷
I don't think you really believe what you're telling me today.
你想调到管理宽松的医院  只是想逃
If I put you in minimum security, you'll just try to escape again.
你得让我看看我儿子
You have to let me see my son.
求求你
Please.
他有生命危险  他需要我帮助
He's in great danger. He's naked without me.
让我打个电话也行
If I could make a phone call...
不行  一会儿也不行
I'm afraid not. Not for a while.
我别无选择
I don't see any choice but to recommend to the review board...
只好再关你半年
that you stay here for another six months.
我要杀了你  混蛋
I'll kill you, you son of a bitch!
- 你这禽兽  - 抓住她
- You son of a bitch! - Get her off!
给她打镇静剂
Ten CCs of sodium amobarbital, stat!
你们这些混蛋
You don't know what you're doing!
快拿药来
Get some restraints in here now!
死到临头了还不觉悟
You don't know what you're doing!
真是个模范公民
Model citizen.
"目标确认"
你刚好错过  15分钟前他们刚走
You just missed him. He was here 15 minutes ago.
- 他们好像要去加利瑞购物中心  - 对
- He was going to the galleria. - Yeah.
加利瑞?
The galleria?
- 我去换些铜板  马上回来  - 好
- I'm gonna get some quarters. I'll be back, all right? - Cool.
- 噢  不  - 小姑娘  你们认识约翰·康纳吗?
- Oh, no! - Girls, do you know John Connor?
不认识
No.
嘿  你认识这个孩子吗?
Hey, do you know this kid?
不  我不认识他
Nah, I don't know him.
- 约翰  - 现在不行
- John. - Not now.
有个条子在找你  快瞧
There's this cop scoping for you. Check it out.
- 他就在那边  - 快溜
- He's right over there. - Split, man.
- 快走  - 好
- Just go. - Yeah.
你在找的人好像往那儿...
I saw that kid...
嘿  你不能跑到这里来
Hey! You're not supposed to be in here!
趴下
Get down.
先生  你没事吧?
Mister, are you all right?
你没事吧?
You all right?
快啊
Come on!
该死
Goddamn!
靠到路边  停车
Okay, time-out. Stop the bike.
停下来
Time-out. Come on, stop the bike.
天啊  别会错意了
Holy shit. Now, don't take this the wrong way.
- 你是终结者  对吧?  - 对
- You are a Terminator, right? - Yes.
生化机械  模型101
Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101.
不可能吧
No.
好家伙
Holy shit.
你真像真的人
You're really real.
我是说
I mean...
你骨子里是机器人  对吧?
You're like a machine underneath, right?
可外表是人形
But alive outside?
内部是机械骨架
I'm a cybernetic organism.
外部是真皮
Living tissue over metal endoskeleton.
真帅
This is intense.
约翰  清醒一下
Get a grip, John. Okay.
你不是来杀我的
You're not here to kill me.
这一点我知道  那你到底要怎样?
I figured that part out for myself. So what's the deal?
我的任务是要保护你
My mission is to protect you.
是吗?  谁派你来的?
Yeah? Who sent you?
是你  35年后的你
You did. Thirty-five years from now...
派我来保护现在的你
you reprogrammed me to be your protector here in this time.
真深奥
Oh, this is deep.
那家伙跟你一样是终结者?
So this other guy, he's a Terminator like you, right?
跟我不同  它是T-1000  是更先进的模型
Not like me. A T-1000, advanced prototype.
你是说它比你更先进?
Your mean more advanced than you are?
- 对  它是特种合金制造  - 那是什么意思?
- Yes. A mimetic poly-alloy. - What the hell does that mean?
- 液态金属  - 我们去哪儿?
- Liquid metal. - Where are we going?
你得立刻离开这座城市  这样才能逃避它的追杀
We have to get out of the city immediately and avoid the authorities.
我想回家去  收拾些东西再走
I gotta stop by my house. I wanna pick up some stuff.
否决  T-1000它一定会在那等你的
Negative. The T-1000 would definitely try to reacquire you there.
- 你确定?  - 我确定
- You sure? - I would.
陶德和吉纳会有危险
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks...
我至少得警告他们
but I gotta warn 'em.
可恶  你有铜板吗?
Shit. You got a quarter?
- 喂  - 吉纳  是我
- Hello. - Janelle, it's me.
- 约翰?  - 一切都好吗?
- John? - Is everything all right?
- 你们都没事吧?  - 当然  甜心  一切都很好
- Are you guys okay? - Sure, honey, everything's okay.
- 你没事吧?  - 我很好
- Are you all right? - Yeah, I'm fine.
约翰  天晚了  我很担心你
John, it's late. I was beginning to worry about you.
你赶快回来  我们一起吃晚餐
If you hurry home, we can sit down and have dinner together.
我正在煮牛肉呢
I'm making beef stew.
不对劲  她对我从没这么好过
Somethings wrong. She's never this nice.
约翰  你在哪儿?
John? Where are you?
那只狗在鬼叫什么劲?
What the hell is the goddamn dog barking at?
闭嘴  你这一文不值的废物
Hey, shut up, you worthless piece of shit!
狗在吠叫
The dog's really barking.
叫那小鬼把那杂种狗丢掉
You were gonna tell the kid to get rid of that mutt.
约翰  天晚了  别害我担心
John, it's late. Please don't make me worry.
他已经在那里了吗?
Could he already be there?
甜心  你没事吧
Honey, are you okay?
- 我在这儿  我没事  - 真的吗?
- I'm right here. I'm fine. - Are you sure you're all right?
- 狗叫什么名字?  - 麦克斯
- What's the dog's name? - Max.
吉纳  伍飞怎么了?
Hey, Janelle. What's wrong with Wolfie?
我听见它在叫  它没事吧?
I can hear him barking. Is he okay?
伍飞很好  甜心  它很好
Wolfie's fine, honey. Wolfie's just fine.
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
你的养父母都死了
Your foster parents are dead.
说清楚点
I need a minute here.
你说这机器能模仿一切事物?
You're telling me that this thing can imitate anything it touches?
只要它能接触到的都行
Anything it samples by physical contact.
厉害
Get real.
那它也能变成一包香烟?
It could disguise itself as a pack of cigarettes?
不行  只能变成类似它大小的物体
No, only an object of equal size.
那为何不变成颗炸弹来杀我?
Why not just become a bomb or something to get me?
它无法变成很复杂的机器
It can't form complex machines.
像枪枝  炸药  化学品等
Guns and explosives have chemicals, moving parts.
但它可以变出一个固态金属形状
It doesn't work that way. But it can form solid metal shapes.
- 像是什么?  - 像刀  能刺的武器
- Like what? - Knives and stabbing weapons.
"麦克斯"
这些是电视监视器照的
These were taken by a video surveillance camera...
1984年  在西城警局
at the West Highland Police Station in 1984.
那晚他杀了17名警察
He killed 17 police officers that night.
都是有家室的人
Men with families...
有子女
children.
这是今天在一个购物中心照的
These were taken at a mall in Reseda...
就在今天
today.
康纳小姐  我们知道你认得此人
Miss Connor, we know you know who this guy is.
我还要告诉你  令郞也失踪了
I just sat here and told you that your son is missing...
他的养父母双双遇害
that the foster parents have been murdered.
我们知道此人涉有重嫌
We know this guy's involved.
此事你一点也不关心?  你关心吗?
Doesn't that mean anything to you? Don't you care?
我们是在浪费时间  咱们走
We're wasting our time. Let's go.
抱歉各位
Sorry, guys.
她越来越与现实生活脱节了
She's grown more disconnected from reality as time goes on.
恐怕她帮不了你们的忙
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
也许等她神智清醒时就可以了  我会通知你们的
If she clears at all and can give us anything, I'll call you.
好吧
Sure.
道格  请带她回房去
Douglas, take her back to her room, please.
是
Yes, sir.
我们走
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
好长一段时间
You see...
我们曾在尼加拉瓜或其他的地方待过
we spent a lot of time in Nicaragua and places like that.
她有阵子跟退役的绿色贝雷帽士兵混
For a while there, she was with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy...
弄了不少枪
running guns.
然后又找了些人
Then there were some other guys.
她向任何可以学习的人吸取经验
She'd shack up with anybody she could learn from...
以便将我造就成伟大的军事领袖
so she could teach me how to be this great military leader.
后来她被捕了
Then she gets busted.
我妈疯狂的举动把我也弄糊涂了
It's like, "Sorry, kid, your mom's a psycho. Didn't you know?"
好像她教我相信的一切是狗屎
Like everything I've been brought up to believe is all made-up bullshit.
我痛恨这一点
I hated her for that.
但她说的一切都是真的
But everything she said was true.
她知道的
She knew...
但没人肯相信她
and nobody believed her...
连我在内
not even me.
我们得把她弄出医院
Listen. We gotta get her out of there.
否决  T-1000精明狡猾
Negative. The T-1000's highest probability for success now...
现在可能已经变成莎拉·康纳  等你去自投罗网
will be to copy Sarah Connor and wait for you to make contact with her.
那她会怎样?
Great. What happens to her?
模仿的对象必须消灭
Typically, the subject being copied is terminated.
糟了  你怎么不早说?  我们得马上走
Shit! Why didn't you tell me? We gotta go right now!
否决  这不是我任务的重点
Negative. It's not a mission priority.
但这是我的重点
Fuck you! She's a priority to me!
混蛋  你是怎么回事?  救命
Goddamn it! What's your problem? Help!
这对我们的任务毫无用处
This does not help our mission.
救命  把这疯子赶走
Get this psycho off of me! Help!
救命  救命呀  他要绑架我  把这疯子赶走
I'm being kidnapped! Get this psycho off of me!
放手
Let me go!
你为何那样做?
Why did you do that?
因为你命令我"放手"
Because you told me to.
什么?
What?
你得照我的话去做  对吧?
You have to do what I say?
那是我任务的一个最高原则
That's one of my mission parameters.
证明呀  用一只脚站立
Prove it. Stand on one foot.
好
Yes!
真酷  只听我命令的终结者
Cool. My own Terminator. Wow.
你没事吧  孩子?
You okay, kid?
滚开  别烦我
Take a hike, bozo.
我们别插手啦
Let's get outta here, man.
去你的  混球
Fuck you, you little dipshit!
混球?
Dipshit?
把脚放下
Put your leg down.
- 你敢叫我混球  - 只是想帮忙
- Did you call moi a dipshit? - Just trying to help this punk.
给这小子点颜色瞧瞧
Grab this guy.
放开我
Get him off of me!
现在谁是混球?
Now who's the dipshit...
- 你个草包  - 放手
- you jock douche bag? - Get off!
不
No.
把枪放下  快
Put the gun down now!
- 离开这儿  - 兄弟  咱们快走
- Get outta here! - Come on. Let's split!
天呀  你会把那人给杀了
You were gonna kill that guy!
当然  我是终结者
Of course. I'm a Terminator.
仔细听我说  好吗?
Listen to me very carefully, okay?
你现在不再是终结者  好吗?
You're not a Terminator anymore, all right?
听懂了吗?
You got that?
你就是不能随便到处杀人
You just can't go around killing people.
为什么?
Why?
什么意思?  反正就是不行
What do you mean, why? 'Cause you can't.
为什么?
Why?
因为你就是不能  好吗?  这件事你得信任我
Because you just can't, okay? Trust me on this.
我要去救我妈
Look. I'm gonna go get my mom.
我命令你要协助我
I order you to help me.
莎拉·康纳在这里吗?
You have a Sarah Connor here?
你来迟了  是吗?
You're runnin' kind of late.
他们已经来了一个多小时
They've been in there for an hour.
等一下  我替你通知
Hold on a second. I'll buzz you in.
你的朋友来了
Oh, here come your friends now.
- 葛兰  要咖啡吗?  - 不  谢了
- Gwen, you want some coffee? - No, thanks.
- 来杯啤酒吧?  - 真爱说笑
- How 'bout a beer? - Yeah, right.
- 我中奖了  - 那可真棒
- Hey, I got a full house. - That's good, Louis.
我走运了
Must be my lucky day.
你说得没错
You're right about number 24.
给24号病房增加药剂量吧
Increase the medication to 250 milligrams.
- 还用同一种药吗?  - 对
- Same kind? - Mm-hmm.
你
You!
你弄断我的手臂了
You broke my arm.
人体内有215块骨头
There are 215 bones in the human body.
不过是断一根而已  不准动
That's one. Now, don't move.
"排水管洗洁剂  有毒"
你想干什么?
What are you going to do?
我们停下来干什么?
Why do we stop now?
你得保证绝不杀人  好吗?
You gotta promise me you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
- 好  - 你发誓
- Right. - Swear?
什么?
What?
举手说  "我绝不杀人"
Just put up your hand and say, "I swear I won't kill anyone."
我发誓我不杀任何人
I swear I will not kill anyone.
好  咱们走
All right. Let's go.
会客时间是十点到四点
Visiting hours is 10:00 to 4:00...
周一到周五
Monday through Friday.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
王八蛋  你开枪打我
You son of a bitch! You shot me!
疯子
Crazy bastard!
别再开枪了  别杀我
Don't shoot me again. Don't kill me.
他死不了的
He'll live.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch!
大家别激动
Let's try to remain calm.
开门  否则他死定了
Open it, or he'll be dead before he hits the floor.
你逃不了的  放开他
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
- 把门打开  - 否则会怎样?
- Open the door. - It ain't gonna happen.
别紧张
Take it easy, Sarah.
行不通的  我知道你不是杀手
It won't work. You're no killer. I don't believe you can do it.
反正你们都得死  索大夫  你知道我很认真
You're already dead. Everybody dies. You know I believe it.
别跟我耍花招
So don't fuck with me!
开门
Open the door!
快开门
退后
Back off!
退回去
Get back!
我会让他死翘翘  我保证
I'll pump him full of this shit. I swear!
退后
Back!
别动
Don't move!
丢掉木棍
Drop the shit!
照做
Do it!
让开
Get in the office.
趴在地上  脸朝下  你过来
On the floor, face down. Not you!
把门打开
Open the door.
趴下  拉好门  面对墙壁
On the floor. Hold it open. Face the wall!
抓住她
Get her!
快打开
Hurry up! Open the door! The door's locked!
快
Let's go! Open it!
- 锁被弄坏了  - 想办法打开
- She broke it off. - Open it!
往那边  快追
Let's go around! Come on! Move it!
不
No.
不
妈  等等
Mom, wait!
休想逃走
Come back here!
不
No.
- 救她呀  - 你别来
- Help her! - Wait here.
- 快帮忙  - 他会把我们都杀死的
- Hurry up! - He'll kill us all!
拉住她
Hold her.
他会杀死我们的
He'll kill us all!
妈  你没事吧  妈
Mom, are you okay? Mom!
想活命就跟我走
Come with me if you want to live.
不要紧  妈  他是来帮忙的
It's okay, Mom. He's here to help.
快走
Go.
它是什么东西?  这到底是怎么回事?
What the fuck is it? What the fuck is going on?
趴下
Get down.
妈
Mon.
下车
Out of the car!
立刻下车
Right now!
走
Go!
子弹没了
I'm out.
- 快点  - 给
- Come on. - Here.
装弹
Reload.
最后一个
Last one!
抓牢
Hang on.
好了
Ready!
约翰
John.
你来开
You, drive.
甩掉他了  后面没人
He's not back there. There's nobody behind us.
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
你看的到路?
Can you see anything?
我看的一清二楚
I see everything.
"路况能见度提升"
酷
Cool.
过来
Come here.
我说过我没事
I said I was okay.
约翰  你来找我真是愚蠢
John, it was stupid of you to go there.
你该有自知之明的
You have to be smarter than that.
你差点连命都送掉
You were almost killed.
你到底在想什么?
What were you thinking?
你不该冒险  为我也不行
You cannot risk yourself, even for me.
你的命太重要了
Do you understand? You're too important.
你懂吗?
Do you understand?
可是...
But...
我必须把你从那儿就出来  对不起
I had to get you out of that place. I'm sorry.
我不需要你协助  我自有办法
I didn't need your help. I can take care of myself.
你的眼睛怎么了?
What's wrong with your eyes?
没什么
Nothing.
你又是什么来头?
So, what's your story?
你没事?
You okay?
很好
Fine.
这机车真不错
Say, that's a nice bike.
轻点行吗?  老粗
Watch it, lug nuts.
你知道自己在干什么吗?
Listen, do you know what you're doing?
我对人体构造非常了解
I have detailed files on human anatomy.
我想也是
I bet.
那使你更容易杀人  是吧?
Makes you a more efficient killer, right?
没错
Correct.
你被击中时会痛吗?
Does it hurt when you get shot?
我感到受损  亦可称为"疼痛"
I sense injuries. The data could be called "pain."
约翰  帮我调整灯光
John, help me with the light.
- 会痊瘉吗?  - 会的
- Will these heal up? - Yes.
那就好  你若不像人  对我们就没用
Good. If you can't pass for human, you're not much good to us.
你能活多久?
How long do you live? I mean, last. Whatever.
我的电池可维持120年
A hundred and twenty years with my existing power cell.
你能学习你电脑中还未输入过的事吗?
Can you learn stuff that you haven't been programmed with...
使你能够
so you can be...
更像人类?
you know, more human...
这样你才不会像个傻蛋
and not such a dork all the time?
我的中央处理器是神经元处理器  也是学习型电脑
My CPU is a neural net processor, a learning computer.
我们外出时天网会将开关设置为"只可读取"
But Skynet presets the switch to read-only when we're sent out alone.
它不想让你有其他思想?
Doesn't want you to do too much thinking, huh?
不可以
No.
能重新设定吗?
Can we reset the switch?
把转子逆时针转动
Rotate the two locking cylinders counterclockwise.
动手
Do it.
把盖子扭开
Now open the port cover.
用力拔出来
Pull to break the seal.
现在把芯片取出来
Good, now remove the shock-damping assembly.
可以看到中央处理器了
You can now access the CPU.
- 看见了吗?  - 看见了
- Do you see it? - Yes.
钳住处理器突起部分
Hold the CPU by its base tab.
"槽口打开"
拔出来
Pull.
看见开关了吗?
Do you see the pin switch?
不要
No! No!
- 与你无关  - 别毁灭他
- Out of my way, John. - Don't kill him.
是"它"  不是"他"  "它"
It, John, not him. It.
好的  是"它"  但我们需要"它"
Okay, it. But we need it.
好好听我说
Listen to me. You listen.
依靠自己的力量比较好
We're better off on our own.
可他是证据
But he's the only proof we have...
是战争以及未来之事的唯一证据
of the future and the war and all that.
也许
Maybe.
可我始终信不过它
I don't trust it.
他是我的朋友  对吧?
But he's my friend, all right?
你根本不知道"它"到底要杀谁
You don't know what it's like to try to kill one of these things...
为了以防万一  这是最后机会  动手吧
and if something goes wrong this could be our last chance, so move!
如果我真是未来领袖
If I'm ever supposed to be this great military leader...
那你总该听一次领袖的意见吧?
maybe you should start listening to my leadership ideas once in a while.
如果亲生母亲都不听我的话
Because if my own mother won't,
那又怎能指望别人?
how do you expect anyone else to?
好吧  听你的吧
All right, play it your way.
"系统中断"
"诊断"
有问题吗?
Was there a problem?
没问题
No problem.
即便有  我也摆平了
None whatsoever.
现在开始学习吧
Are we learning yet?
我们得尽量远离这座城市
We have to get as far away from the city as possible.
往南走
Just head south.
时速别超过65英里
Keep it under 65.
- 否则会被交警拦下  - 确认
- We don't want to be pulled over. - Affirmative.
不  不不
No, no, no.
你得学人类说话的方式
You gotta listen to the way people talk.
你不能说"确认"那种鸟话
You don't say "affirmative" or some shit like that.
你要说  "没问题"
You say, "No problemo."
如果有人找碴  你就说  "有种试试看"
If someone comes off to you with an attitude, you say, "Eat me."
如果要解决掉他们  就说"拜拜了  宝贝"
And if you want to shine them on, it's "Hasta la vista, baby."
拜拜了  宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
对  或者说  "去死吧  精虫"
Yeah, or "Later, dick-wad."
有人生气  你就说  "冷静点"
If someone gets upset, you say, "Chill out."
或者你也可以自由发挥
Or you can do combinations.
冷静点  精虫
Chill out, dick-wad.
对  看  你真的会了
That's great. See? You're getting it.
没问题
No problemo.
你身上带钱了吗?
You got any cash?
有几百块  分你一半
I got a couple hundred bucks. I'll give you half.
妈
Mom!
我去买点吃的
Get some food.
一点幽默感都没有
No sense of humor.
还有件事  你要放松点
That's another thing. You can lighten up a bit yourself.
一本正经已经很老土了
This severe routine is getting old, okay.
你得这学着风趣一点
I mean, you're acting like such a geek.
时常微笑一下
Smile once in a while.
微笑
Smile?
对  微笑  看着
Yeah, you know, smile. Watch.
嗨  真是个好地方  生意不错吧?
Hi. Nice place you got here. How's business?
别捣乱
Give me a break.
演砸了
Okay, bad example.
看见那个小伙子了吗?
See that guy over there?
那就是微笑
That's a smile.
"动作选择"
"分析"
不错
That's good.
找个镜子多练习一下吧
Maybe you could practice in front of a mirror or something.
要吃点薯条吗?
Want some of my fries?
- 你需要帮忙吗?  - 不用
- Need any help? - No.
- 我杀死你了  - 不  你没有
- I got you! - No, you didn't!
- 你死了  - 才没有呢
去你的  混球
I got you!
我们撑不过去  对吧
We're not gonna make it, are we?
我是指人类
People, I mean.
你们天性便有自我毁灭倾向
It's in your nature to destroy yourselves.
对  真无聊  是吧?
Yeah. Major drag, huh?
快住手  要不掐断你们脖子
Break it up before I wring both of your necks.
我要知道"天网"系统的起源
I need to know how Skynet gets built.
是谁研究出来的?
Who's responsible?
直接负责的人是莫斯·戴森
The man most directly responsible is Miles Bennett Dyson.
谁呀?
Who is that?
塞柏电脑公司特别企划室主任
He's the director of special projects at Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
为何是他?
Why him?
数月内他会研制出新型微电脑
In a few months, he creates a revolutionary type of microprocessor.
然后呢?
Go on. Then what?
三年内塞柏会成为军方电脑来源
In three years Cyberdyne will become the largest supplier...
负责高阶研发
of military computer systems.
所有轰炸机都会装载塞柏的电脑系统
All Stealth bombers are upgraded with Cyberdyne computers...
成为无人操作机型
becoming fully unmanned.
然后它创造了完美的运作记录
Afterwards they fly with a perfect operational record.
天网计划法案正式通过
The Skynet funding bill is passed.
1997年8月4日  电脑系统上线
The system goes on-line on August 4, 1997.
它迅速掌握战略防卫系统
Human decisions are removed from strategic defense.
天网电脑以极快速度吸取经验
Skynet begins to learn at a geometric rate.
它产生自我意识  时间为8月29日上午2时14分
It becomes self-aware at 2:14 a.m. Eastern time, August 29.
人类惊慌失措  准备应变
In a panic, they try to pull the plug.
- 但天网却先发制人  - 是的
- Skynet fights back. - Yes.
它向俄罗斯境内目标发射飞弹
It launches its missiles against the targets in Russia.
为何攻击俄国?  他们现在不是我们的朋友吗?
Why attack Russia? Aren't they our friends now?
天网知道俄方反击便可消灭美国
Skynet knows the Russian counterattack will eliminate its enemies over here.
天啦
Jesus.
你对戴森了解多少?
How much do you know about Dyson?
我有他的详细资料
I have detailed files.
我要知道一切
I want to know everything.
他的长相  住址  一切
What he looks like, where he lives, everything.
莫斯
Miles.
你打算工作一整天吗?
Are you going to work all day?
对不起  这玩意儿很伤脑筋
I'm sorry, baby. But this thing is just kicking my ass.
今天是礼拜天
Miles, it's Sunday.
你答应带孩子去水上乐园的
You promised to take the kids to Raging Waters today.
不行吧
I can't...
我忙死了
I'm on a roll.
亲爱的  这东西面世后会轰动全球的
Baby, this is going to blow them all away.
- 神经元处理器  - 你说过的
- It's a neural net processor. - I know. You told me.
这是神经元处理器  可以像人类一样思考
It's a neural net processor. It thinks and learns like we do.
是常温条件下的超导体
It's superconducting at room temperature.
其他电脑就像计算器一样弱智
Other computers are just pocket calculators by comparison.
真的这么重要吗?
But why is that so goddamn important, Miles?
我真的想知道
I really need to know...
有时候我真的要疯了
because sometimes I feel like I'm going crazy here.
亲爱的  我快成功了
Baby, I am this close.
过来
Come here.
想象一下  一架喷气机
Imagine a jet airliner...
上面的机师永不疲倦  永不出错
with a pilot that never gets tired, never makes mistakes...
不会像个醉猫跑来上班
never shows up to work with a hangover.
来见过这位机师
Meet the pilot.
我们为什么要结婚?  为什么要生孩子?
Why did we get married, Miles? Why did we have these children?
你根本不需要我们
You don't need us.
你的身心全在这里
Your heart and your mind are in here.
可这东西不会像我们一样爱你
But it doesn't love you like we do.
我很抱歉  真的
I'm sorry. Really.
带孩子们出去玩吧
How about spending some time with your other babies?
水上乐园
Raging Waters!
在车上等着
Wait in the car.
你真性急  康纳
You're pretty jumpy, Connor.
你也是
You too.
约翰
Hey, big John.
你好
What's up?
他是谁?
Who is this guy?
他没问题  他跟我来的
He's cool, Enrique. He's with me.
他是  包伯叔
He's... Uncle Bob.
包伯叔  这是恩里克
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
包伯叔?
Uncle Bob, huh?
好吧  自己人
Okay.
要喝吗?
Drink?
包伯叔?
"Uncle Bob"?
你们很有名  都上了电视
You're pretty famous, all over the goddamn TV.
条子就像疯狗似的
Pictures of you, John, your big friend here.
想揪你们出来呢
Cops are going nuts looking for you.
我需要衣物  食物  和一辆卡车
I just came for my stuff. I need clothes, food and a truck.
要不要我连假牙都一起给你?
How about the fillings in my teeth?
现在就要
Now, Enrique.
你们也去  去拿武器
You two, you're on weapons detail.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
我妈有个特点
One thing about my mom...
她总是未雨绸缪
she always plans ahead.
好极了
Excellent.
这是最好的车  但缺起动马达
This is my best truck, but the starter motor's gone.
你有时间等它装好吗?
You got time to change it out?
- 可以  我要等午夜之后再越过边境  - 那好
- Yeah. I'm gonna wait till dark to cross the border. - Okay.
恩里克
Enrique.
这里很危险  今晚你也得离开
It's dangerous for you here. You get out tonight too, okay?
好的
Sure.
我早把生死置之度外
Just drop by anytime and totally fuck up my life, all right?
我在这种地方长大
See, I grew up in places like this...
我还以为人就是这样过活
so I just thought that's how people lived...
驾驶着直升机
riding around in helicopters...
学习如何炸东西
learning how to blow shit up.
我妈妈被捕后
But then when my mom got busted...
我被送进学校
I got put into a regular school.
发现其他孩子都在玩任天堂
All the other kids were into Nintendo.
你害怕过吗?
Are you ever afraid?
没有
No.
也没怕过死?
Not even of dying?
没有
No.
你对死亡从来都无动于衷?
You don't feel any emotion about it, one way or another?
是的  任务完成前  我得保持机体稳定运行
No. I have to stay functional until my mission is complete.
所以死不足惧
Then it doesn't matter.
我也得保持稳定  "我太重要了"
I have to stay functional too. "I'm too important."
很适合你
That's definitely you.
与我妈来往的男人都是怪人
Most of the guys my mom hung around with were geeks...
但有个家伙倒很酷
but there was this one guy, he was kinda cool.
他教我玩这些
He taught me engines.
撑住这儿
Hold here.
后来他们还是分手了
Mom screwed it up, of course.
她总是在谈审判日等等之类的话题
She'd always tell 'em about Judgment Day...
也许直到今天
and me being this world leader.
她脑里仍只想这一件事
That'd be all she wrote.
请把钳子给我
Torque wrench, please.
拿去
Here.
真希望能见到我生父
I wish I could've met my real dad.
你会的
You will.
对
Yeah, I guess.
那时我已经45岁了
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
我会派他回到1984年
They sent him back through time to 1984.
天啦
Man.
他现在还没出生呢
He hasn't even been born yet.
真不可思议
It messes with your head.
- 把螺丝帽给我  - 给
- The other bolt. - Oh. Here.
她只和他共处了一个晚上
Mom and him were only together for one night.
我想她仍爱着他
She still loves him, I guess.
有时我看见她在哭
I see her crying sometimes.
当然啦  她完全否认  她说那是有异物吹进眼里
She denies it totally, of course, like she got something stuck in her eye.
你们为何哭泣?
Why do you cry?
- 你是说人类?  - 对
- You mean people? - Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
他们就是会哭
We just cry...
尤其是"伤心"的时候
you know, when it hurts.
是"伤"造成的?
Pain causes it?
不  那不一样
No. It's different.
虽然你没事  但伤心时就会哭
It's when there's nothing wrong with you, but you hurt anyway.
- 懂吗?  - 不懂
- You get it? - No.
那才像话
All right, my man!
没问题
No problemo.
击掌庆祝
Give me five.
像这样撑开手掌  来
Just put out your hand like this, come on.
很好  拍打我的手  该你了  你来击掌
All right! Now hit me. Give me five. Do the same thing.
很好
All right!
好  很好  来个高的
Okay, that's good. Up high.
低的
Five low.
你慢了
Too slow.
我是在开玩笑  再来一次
I'm just kidding. One more time.
很好  接着来
Good. Now try it.
来  打我一掌
Now do me. Give me five.
看到约翰和机器人在一起  突然真相大白了
Watching John with the machine, it was suddenly so clear.
终结者绝不罢休
The Terminator would never stop.
绝不离开他  它不会伤害他
It would never leave him, never hurt him...
不会向他叫骂  不会酒醉打他
never shout at him or get drunk and hit him...
或是藉口太忙没空陪他
or be too busy to spend time with him.
它永远会在他身边
It would always be there...
它会拼命保卫他
and it would die to protect him.
这些年来  我遇到过许多男人
Of all the would-be fathers who came and went over the years...
这东西  这机器
this thing, this machine...
却是唯一有资格当他父亲的人
was the only one who measured up.
在这疯狂世界里
In an insane world...
这是最佳选择
it was the sanest choice.
我们来玩玩这个
Hey, let's try this one.
来吧
There we go.
"不是命运"
她叫你们按原计划向南走
She said go south with him like you planned.
- 她明天会赶上你们  - 妈
- She'll meet you tomorrow. - Mom!
妈等等
Mom, wait!
"不是命运"
"No fate."
命运是要自己开创的
No fate but what we make.
我的父亲告诉她的
My father told her this.
是未来的我让我父亲告诉她的
I made him memorize it in the future as a message to her.
算了
Never mind.
整件事就是这样
Okay, the whole thing goes...
一切尚未成为定局
The future's not set.
未来仍可以自己去开创
There's no fate but what we make for ourselves.
她想改变未来?
She intends to change the future.
对  我猜也是
Yeah, I guess.
糟了
Oh, shit!
- 戴森  - 对
- Dyson. - Yeah.
一定是的  莫斯·戴森
Gotta be. Miles Dyson.
她想要杀了戴森
She's gonna blow him away.
来  咱们走
Come on! Let's go!
快啊
Come on!
事实上  这样做非常危险
This is tactically dangerous.
开快点
Drive faster.
T-1000跟我一样了解情况
The T-1000 has the same files that I do.
它知道我知道的一切  它还能预测敌人的行动
It knows what I know. It might anticipate this move.
我不管  咱们得阻止她
I don't care. We gotta stop her.
杀死戴森的确有可能阻止战争
Killing Dyson might prevent the war.
我不管  你还没学通吗?
I don't care! Haven't you learned anything yet?
你还不明白为何不能乱杀人吗?
Haven't you figured out why you can't kill people?
听着  也许你不在乎生死
Look, maybe you don't care if you live or die...
可并非所有人都这样
but everybody's not like that.
人类有感情  会受到伤害  会感到恐惧
We have feelings. We hurt. We're afraid.
这种东西你要理解  我不是开玩笑  真的很重要
You got to learn this stuff. I'm not kidding. It's important.
丹尼  叫你去睡觉  我说真的
Danny, I told you to go to bed, like your sister.
再玩一会儿就好  妈
Just a couple of minutes, Mom!
丹尼  睡觉时间到了
Danny, your time is up!
快刷牙上床
Come brush your teeth and get to bed.
丹尼
Danny.
爸
Daddy!
这不是游戏  快逃
Danny, go! Go!
莫斯
Miles.
- 特瑞莎  跑  - 我的天啊
- Tarissa, run! - Oh, my God!
快带丹尼走  快逃
Just take Danny and run!
快逃
Run!
我的天呀
Oh, Jesus! Miles!
爹地
Daddy!
丹尼
Danny.
谁都不许动
Nobody fucking move!
别伤害我爸
Don't hurt my daddy!
趴到地上
On the floor, bitch.
趴下
Get down now!
让开
Get out of the way!
别伤害他
Don't hurt him!
让开  否则我开枪
Get on the floor now!
饶了孩子吧
Just let the boy go.
你闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up.
闭嘴
Shut up!
都是你的错  混蛋
It's all your fault, motherfucker.
- 都是你的错  - 什么?
- It's all your fault! - What?
我不会让你得逞的
I'm not gonna let you do it.
糟了  太迟了
Shit! We're too late!
看看他们
Check them.
看着我  妈
Look at me, Mom.
你受伤了?
Are you hurt?
看着我
Look at me.
我几乎
I almost...
我下不了手
放心吧
It'll be okay.
一定还有办法的  真的
We'll figure something out. Okay?
相信我吧
I promise.
你是来阻止我的?
You came here to stop me.
对
Yeah, I did.
我爱你  约翰
I love you, John.
我一直爱着你
I always have.
我知道
I know.
子弹贯穿
Deep penetration.
没有击碎骨头
No shattered bone.
把伤口压着就能止住血了
Hold here. The pressure should stop the bleeding.
你们是谁?
Who are you people?
告诉他
Show him.
丹尼  你跟我走好吗?  带我看看你房间
Danny, I want you to come with me right now. Show me your room.
我的天呀
Oh, my God.
仔细听我说
Now listen to me very carefully.
戴森听着终结者的解说
Dyson listened while the Terminator laid it all down.
天网  审判日
Skynet. Judgment Day.
未来的历史
The history of things to come.
知道自己的研发成果最终将会
It's not every day that you find out you're responsible...
害死三十亿人
for three billion deaths.
他的反应还算好
He took it pretty well.
我想我要呕吐了
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
你是为了
You're judging me...
我还未做的事惩罚我?
on things I haven't even done yet.
我怎会知道?
How were we supposed to know?
对
Yeah.
没错
Right.
你怎会知道?
How were you supposed to know?
氢弹就是你这种人发明的
Fucking men like you built the hydrogen bomb.
也是你这种人
Men like you...
引爆它的
thought it up.
你以为你很有创造力
You think you're so creative.
你根本就不知道创造的意义
You don't know what it's like to really create something...
创造生命
to create a life...
是感觉它在体内成长
to feel it growing inside you.
你只会创造死亡和毁灭
All you know how to create is death and destruction.
妈
Mom!
你得说些有建设性的话  好吗?
We need to be a little more constructive here. Okay?
我们仍要阻止战争的  对吧?
We still have to stop this from happening, don't we?
但我以为
But I thought...
我们是要通过改变现在的事  从而改变未来的事吗?
Aren't we changing things right now, changing the way it goes?
没错
That's right.
本来就快做出超级新电脑
There's no way I'm going to finish the new processor. Not now.
现在一切免谈  我不干了  我明天就辞职
Forget it. I'm out of it. I'll quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
那还不够好
That's not good enough.
不能让别人继续完成你的工作
No one must follow your work.
好吧
Right.
那得摧毁实验室的一切装备
All right, then we have to destroy all the stuff at the lab...
档案  磁碟机
the files, the disk drives...
所有的一切
everything here.
一切资料
Everything.
我不在乎
I don't care.
晶片
The chip.
- 你们知道晶片吗?  - 什么晶片?
- Do you know about the chip? - What chip?
他们把它锁在金库里  是跟你一样的机器人身上的
It's at Cyberdyne. It's from the other one like you.
第一代终结者的记忆体
The CPU from the first Terminator.
混蛋  我就知道
Son of a bitch! I knew it!
他们不准我们问晶片是哪儿来的
They told us not to ask where they got it.
真聪明的混蛋
Those lying motherfuckers.
它很可怕  但非常先进
It's scary stuff. Radically advanced.
它被砸烂了
It was smashed.
无法运作  但它给了我许多不可思议的灵感
It didn't work, but it gave us ideas, took us in new directions.
前所未有
Things we would've never...
我的工作全是以它为基础
All my work was based on it.
必须摧毁它
It must be destroyed.
你能带我们通过警卫吗?
Can you get us in? Past security?
我想可以  什么时候去?
I think so, yeah. When?
现在?
Now?
未来对我而言已成为
The future, always so clear to me...
深夜中的一条看不见的公路
had become like a black highway at night.
而人类在未加分隔的领域中
We were in uncharted territory now...
在前进的旅程上不断创造历史
making up history as we went along.
"塞柏电脑公司"
你是卡尔吧?
Carl, right?
我一些外地朋友
Friends from out of town. I just thought I'd...
我只想带他们上楼四处瞧瞧
take 'em upstairs and show 'em around.
戴森先生  你也知道规定  带客人进实验室时
Mr. Dyson, you know the rules concerning visitors in the lab.
我需要书面许可
I need written authorization...
我坚持
I insist.
你休想妄动
Don't even think about it.
行了
It's okay.
开金库要两把钥匙  而且得同时插入旋转
It takes two keys, turned simultaneously, to open the vault.
另一支在警卫室里
The other one is in a locker at the security station.
吉文
Gibbons?
吉文  老兄
Gibbons! Come on, man!
你不能擅离岗位的
You can't leave the desk like that!
吉文
Gibbons!
糟糕
Oh, shit.
我的卡片应该可以开启它
My card should access this.
什么?
What?
- 怎么回事?  - 可恶
- What is it? - Damn it.
警报器已经启动
The silent alarm's been tripped.
它使所有启动密码都失效了
It's neutralized all the codes in the entire building.
现在到处都不通了
Nothing will open anywhere now.
我们得放弃此事
We have to abort.
不
No.
我们干到底
We go all the way. Okay?
你们在实验室开始行动  我能打开这个
You guys get started on the lab. I can open this.
- 是大闹商场的家伙  - 是那家伙
- I think it's that guy from the mall. - It is.
对  是他和那女人
Yeah. It's him and the woman.
立即总动员到这里来
Just send everything you got in the area right now.
我的私人密码可能还能通
I have a personal entry code for the lab. It may still work.
没有用
It's no good.
试试我的法子
Let me try mine.
约翰  小心
John, fire in the hole!
且慢  现在不能进去  火焰启动了"海龙消防系统"
Wait! You can't go in there. The fire set off the Halon system.
等几分钟  要让毒气消散
You have to wait until the gas clears.
戴防毒面具
Put this on.
来吧  开工了
All right, let's get to work.
所有管区及可以应召的各组注意
All units in the vicinity and all units able to respond...
在克拉马街2144号塞柏大厦里
a 211 in progress, 2144 Kramer Street, the Cyberdyne building.
发生犯罪事件
Suspect one is white female...
嫌犯一为白种女性  莎拉·康纳
identified as last name Connor, first name Sarah.
昨晚从州立精神病院逃脱
Escaped last night from Pescadero State Hospital.
嫌犯二为白种男性
Suspect two: White male...
我办公室的所有磁碟
All the disks in my office...
以及那边办公室的所有磁碟
all the disks in that office over there...
还有我桌子里的所有东西
everything behind my desk...
所有的处理器
and all the processors on my left.
这些东西我们要全毁掉
We'll blow those with the C4.
能不能
Can I...
打搅一下
Excuse me.
那东西能借我用用吗?
Can I borrow that thing?
我为它花费多年心血
I worked a lot of years on this thing.
123  请再次报告方位
One-Mary-23, give me that location again.
2111  克拉莫
2111 Kramer.
嫌犯携有武器极度危险
Suspects are armed and considered extremely dangerous.
好了
All right.
7-2-5-6
7-2-5-6.
赚到了
Easy money.
糟糕  不好了
Oh, shit. Not good.
进展如何?
How we doing?
已经定时
Primer cord is set.
再来一桶  再等两分钟
One more barrel, two more minutes.
- 我们如何引爆?  - 遥控引爆
- How do we set them off? - Remote control.
轻而易举
Piece of cake.
- 有人来了  - 是警察?
- We got company. - Police?
- 有多少人?  - 大概倾巢而出
- How many? - All of 'em, I think.
你们走  我来解决这儿
Go. I'll finish here.
快点
Come on.
我来对付警察
I'll take care of the police.
等一下  你发过誓
Wait! You swore!
相信我
Trust me.
窗台上的人
You at the window!
丢下武器  把双手放在头上
Drop your weapon and place your hands on top of your head!
老天
Holy shit!
是机关枪
That's a mini-gun!
- 快走  - 天啦
- Come on! - Oh, shit!
快走
Go! Go! Go!
"死伤人数: 零"
开火
Fire!
同时向左转
Same time, to the left.
一  二  三  开始
One, two, three, go.
好了  我告诉你怎么开
All right. In order to get that out...
我们抓住天网的命脉了
We got Skynet by the balls now.
快走吧
Come on, let's book.
停火
Hold your fire!
- 准备好了吗?  - 好了
- Ready to rock? - Ready.
该走了
Time to go.
马上
Now.
- 拿着  他们会用催泪瓦斯  - 快走
- Take this. They'll use gas. - Come on.
快去开门  莫斯  把引爆器给我
Get started on the door. Miles, hand me the detonator.
妈
Mom! Mom!
可恶
Shit!
她被困在清洁室了  没法出来
She's in the clean room. There's no way outta there.
趴下
Get down!
给
Here.
我不知还能抓住这玩意儿多久
I don't know how much longer I can hold this.
是炸弹
Fall back!
大家出去
Everybody out!
炸弹  快跑
Fall back now! Go! Go! Go!
这里已经演变成战场
We got a war zone here!
"状况预测"
眼睛闭上
Shut your eyes.
待在这儿  我马上回来
Stay here. I'll be back.
趴在地上  面朝下
Get down on the floor! Face down!
趴在地上
On the floor now!
行啦  干掉他
Okay, drop him!
你拿着
Here, hold this.
走
Go!
该死
Shit!
出去
Get out.
听着
Listen.
不管怎样你都要躲好
No matter what happens, stay under these vests.
- 懂吗?  - 懂
- You got it? - Yeah.
好的
All right.
直升机来了
Chopper's coming in!
是它
It's him.
可恶
Shit!
约翰  趴好
John. Stay down!
妈
Mom.
天呐  你没事吧?
Goddamn! You all right?
妈  快起来  我们得出去
Come on, Mom, we gotta get out.
- 拿着散弹枪  - 好的
- Take the shotgun. - Okay.
你受伤了吗?
Are you hurt?
"液化氮"
糟糕  加油  妈
Holy shit. Come on, Mom. Come on!
- 我需要你的卡车  - 快
- We need your truck. - Hurry!
- 来  快点  - 上车
- Come on. Hurry. - Get in.
走
Go!
搞什么
What the hell...
- 血止不住  - 继续施压
- I'm bleeding bad. - Keep pressure on it.
这样很奏效
Here. This'll work.
他越来越近了
He's gaining.
加油
Step on it!
- 这是最高速了  - 我跑的都比它快
- This is the vehicle's top speed. - I can run faster than this!
朝右追来了
Coming up, to the right.
小心
Watch it! Watch it!
- 替我开  - 你上哪儿去?
- Drive. - Where are you going?
走左边
Take the off-ramp.
可恶
Shit!
抓稳了
Hold on!
别停
Don't stop!
一直走
Go straight!
- 小心  - 闪开
- Look out! - Duck!
快离开这儿
Get the hell outta here!
快离开这儿  快
Get outta here! Let's go! Come on!
拜拜了  宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
我们的时间并不多
We don't have much time.
咱们走
Let's go.
快点  我们得离开这儿
Come on! We gotta get outta here.
快点  起来
Come on! Get up!
把散弹枪给我
Hand me the shotgun.
妈  我扶你走
Put your weight on me, Mom.
快呀
Hurry!
忍着点
Come on, Mom.
快起来
Get up!
走这边
This way. Come on.
不  等等
No! Wait!
等等  太热了  回头
Wait. No. No. It's too hot. Go back.
- 快跑  - 不  我们得一起走
- Go. Run. - No! We gotta stick together.
约翰  快走
John, you've got to go now.
- 约翰  - 快走
- John! - Go! Now!
不
No!
"目标搜寻"
爬上去
Get up the steps.
上去
Go.
快
Get up.
抓牢  我扶你  快
Come on, Mom. I got you.
抓住链子  抓好
Grab the chain. Grab it.
抓住它  快走
Grab it. Go. Go!
妈  快来啊
Mom, come on! Mom!
把约翰叫来
Call to John.
不
No!
我知道这样很痛
I know this hurts.
把他叫来
Call John.
快叫约翰过来
Call to John now.
去你的
Fuck you.
"备用能源"
约翰
John.
救命
Help!
约翰
John.
妈
Mom.
- 救我  - 让开  约翰
- Help me. - Get out of the way, John.
约翰
John! John!
开枪
Shoot!
妈
Mom!
趴下
Get down!
起来  加油
Get up. Come on.
天呀
Holy shit.
我需要疗养
I need a vacation.
它死了吗?
Is it dead?
被终结掉了
Terminated.
这个也丢掉?
Will this melt in there?
对  丢下去
Yes. Throw it in.
再见
Adios.
还有晶片
And the chip.
结束了
It's over.
不
No.
还有一个晶片
There's one more chip.
它也得摧毁掉
And it must be destroyed also.
给
Here.
我不能终结我自己  你得把我放到下面的钢水里去
I cannot self-terminate. You must lower me into the steel.
不
No.
抱歉  约翰
I'm sorry, John. I'm sorry.
不  你留在我们身边不要紧的
No, it'll be okay. Stay with us.
- 没关系的  - 我必须离开
- It'll be okay. - I have to go away.
不  别这样  请别走
No, don't do it. Please, don't go.
我必须离开
I must go away, John.
不
No!
不  等等
No, wait.
- 你不必这样做  - 抱歉
- You don't have to do this. - I'm sorry.
不  别这样  别走
No, don't do it! Don't go!
这一切必须结束
It has to end here.
我命令你不要走
I order you not to go!
我现在知道你们为什么会哭了
I know now why you cry.
但那是我永远做不到的事
But it's something I can never do.
再见
Good-bye.
不可知的未来在我们面前展开
The unknown future rolls toward us.
我头一次充满希望的面对它
I face it for the first time with a sense of hope.
全因为一台机器  一名终结者
Because if a machine, a Terminator...
它学到了人类生命的价值
can learn the value of human life...
也许我们也办的到
maybe we can too.